Peace and Justice Studies Records UA086
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Peace and Justice Studies Records
1980 -- 2015
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Center for Interdisciplinary Studies
Peace and Justice Studies
Bryan, Dale
UA086
26.4 Linear Feet 22 record cartons
This collection contains the records of the Peace and Justice Studies program.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by Peace and Justice Studies, 2011-2017.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into nine series: Institute in Social Movements and Strategic Nonviolence [The Summer Institute]; Curricula; Professional Development; Co-curricular; Internal Administration; Event Files; Student Work; Publications and Publicity; and 2017 accessions.
Biographical / Historical
Peace and Justice Studies and Communications and Media Studies were established in the Experimental College as satellite programs sometime after 1979. In 1990 the faculty approved independent status for Peace and Justice Studies, and it became a major in the School of Arts and Sciences.
The Peace and Justice Studies Program (PJS) was founded to provide students an academic means to integrate an understanding of the many crises facing the world and to encourage involvement in nonviolent attempts to build a world of peace and justice. Education, particularly higher education, offers a valuable setting for creating peace and justice through study and active involvement in social change processes. PJS is dedicated to working to provide a university-wide forum for the discussion of these issues. PJS sponsors or co-sponsors numerous educational events and community activities to enrich and expand classroom work.
PJS is administered by an Executive Board that includes faculty, staff, and students. This Board sets overall policy, helps shape the curricula and activities of the Program, and often organizes co-curricular events for the entire campus. The goal is to encourage different types of interaction to help create and sustain an engaged learning community.
In 1991 a summer program known as the Institute in Social Movements and Strategic Nonviolence was founded. It is also referred to as the Summer Institute. In 2000, an additional distinction is made between the Peace Institute and the River Institute. Students performed summer internships with the New England Peace Studies Association and Educators for Peace. 2000 marked the tenth anniversary of the Institute in Social Movements and Strategic Nonviolence Program.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the records of the Peace and Justice Studies program at Tufts University. The collection includes materials on curriculum development, professional development, summer institutes, program development, student work, publications, and administrative files. The collection also contains the files of Dale Bryan, former director of the Peace and Justice Studies (PJS) program, including curriculum development, program and event files, board minutes and grant files, and personal writings.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Academic Departments and Programs; Curriculum and Instruction -- Teaching Material; Curriculum and Instruction -- Student Work
- Institute in Social Movements and Strategic Nonviolence [The Summer Institute], 1990 -- 2005; UA086.001; 10.8 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains planning documents and curricula related to the Institute in Social Movements and Strategic Nonviolence, also known as The Summer Institute, starting in 1991. In 2000, an additional distinction is made between the Peace Institute and the River Institute. Also included are records of applicants to the program.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  75 years from the date of creation.
  - 1991 Inst. Applications, UA086.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - 1991 Follow-up questionaire, UA086.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Seminar notes - 1991 Instit., UA086.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Evaluations, 1991; UA086.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - 1991 Inst. Data, UA086.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Juan Capella, 1991; UA086.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Jennifer Evans, 1991; UA086.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Daniel Finn, 1991; UA086.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Ginny Hamilton, 1991; UA086.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Sandra Hanna, 1991; UA086.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Kathleen King, 1991; UA086.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Richard Nikas, 1991; UA086.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Gretchen Nyman, 1991; UA086.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - David Plante, 1991; UA086.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Ron Zornes, 1991; UA086.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - 1992 Inst. Grades/papers, UA086.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Institute Applicants, 1992; UA086.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Institute Sites, 1992; UA086.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Kyoko Imai, 1992; UA086.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Ken Norton, 1992; UA086.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Lou Taylor, 1992; UA086.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Tammy Welter, 1992; UA086.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - 1993 Inst./EDF Proposal, UA086.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - 1993 Inst. Evaluations, UA086.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - 1993 Inst. Applications, UA086.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - 1993 Inst. Sites, UA086.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - 1993 Inst. EDF/EJM, UA086.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - Alex Brozan, 1993; UA086.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - Miho Fukushima, 1993; UA086.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - D'Vell Garrison, 1993; UA086.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Karin Johnson, 1993; UA086.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Doug Kehlhem, 1993; UA086.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Marjorie McFarlane, 1993; UA086.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Jen Maler, 1993; UA086.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Shawntell Manning, 1993; UA086.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Bayyinah Morton, 1993; UA086.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Leslie Routman, 1993; UA086.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Jodi Sugerman, 1993; UA086.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Timothy Wolter, 1993; UA086.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - Grace Talusan, 1993; UA086.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - Abdu Salaam Moulta Ali, 1994; UA086.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - Marjory Charlot, 1994; UA086.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - Selene de la Pena, 1994; UA086.001.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - Charlene Desir, 1994; UA086.001.002.00016 (Box 2)
  - Brenda Lewis, 1994; UA086.001.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - Jen Mallette, 1994; UA086.001.002.00018 (Box 2)
  - Trecia McDermott, 1994; UA086.001.002.00019 (Box 2)
  - Alisa Orduna, 1994; UA086.001.002.00020 (Box 2)
  - Julie Sze, 1994; UA086.001.002.00021 (Box 2)
  - Julie Walleisa, 1994; UA086.001.002.00022 (Box 2)
  - Carolyn White, 1994; UA086.001.002.00023 (Box 2)
  - Institute Evaluations, 1994; UA086.001.002.00024 (Box 2)
  - Institute Grades, 1994; UA086.001.002.00025 (Box 2)
  - Institute Sites, 1994; UA086.001.002.00026 (Box 2)
  - EDF/EIM Institute Class Notes, 1994; UA086.001.002.00027 (Box 2)
  - Institute Applications, 1994; UA086.001.002.00028 (Box 2)
  - Institute Evaluations- Midterm, 1994; UA086.001.002.00029 (Box 2)
  - Nebiat Woldemichael, 1994; UA086.001.002.00030 (Box 2)
  - Curriculum Development, 1 of 9, 1994; UA086.001.002.00031 (Box 2)
  - Curriculum Development, 2 of 9, 1994; UA086.001.002.00032 (Box 2)
  - Curriculum Development, 3 of 9, 1994; UA086.001.002.00033 (Box 2)
  - Curriculum Development, 4 of 9, 1994; UA086.001.002.00034 (Box 2)
  - Curriculum Development, 5 of 9, 1994; UA086.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Curriculum Development, 6 of 9, 1994; UA086.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Curriculum Development, 7 of 9, 1994; UA086.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Curriculum Development, 8 of 9, 1994; UA086.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Curriculum Development, 9 of 9, 1994; UA086.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Photos, 1994 -- 1995; UA086.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Institute Applications, 1 of 2, 1995; UA086.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Institute Applications, 2 of 2, 1995; UA086.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Institute Fundraising, 1995; UA086.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - Institute Evaluations, 1995; UA086.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Course Evaluations PJS99A/100A Dale Bryan, 1995; UA086.001.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - EDF Institute, 1995; UA086.001.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - Institute Applications/ Etc., 1995; UA086.001.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - Cecie Cedillo, 1995; UA086.001.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - Gina Coplon, 1995; UA086.001.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - Kevin Emerson, 1995; UA086.001.003.00016 (Box 3)
  - Eric Pliner, 1995; UA086.001.003.00017 (Box 3)
  - Mary Prime, 1995; UA086.001.003.00018 (Box 3)
  - Irene Tom, 1995; UA086.001.003.00019 (Box 3)
  - Keyshia Williams, 1995; UA086.001.003.00020 (Box 3)
  - Orlena Yee, 1995; UA086.001.003.00021 (Box 3)
  - Ariane Bertrand, 1996; UA086.001.003.00022 (Box 3)
  - Greg Czarnelki, 1996; UA086.001.003.00023 (Box 3)
  - Christina Leano, 1996; UA086.001.003.00024 (Box 3)
  - Steven Henderson, 1996; UA086.001.003.00025 (Box 3)
  - Micha Josephy, 1996; UA086.001.003.00026 (Box 3)
  - Cindy Ko, 1996; UA086.001.003.00027 (Box 3)
  - Julie MacDonald, 1996; UA086.001.003.00028 (Box 3)
  - Martha Mazariegos, 1996; UA086.001.003.00029 (Box 3)
  - Shontae Praileau, 1996; UA086.001.003.00030 (Box 3)
  - Rebecca Steinbach, 1996; UA086.001.003.00031 (Box 3)
  - Shelly Stokes, 1996; UA086.001.003.00032 (Box 3)
  - Student Evaluations, 1996; UA086.001.003.00033 (Box 3)
  - 1996 Apps, UA086.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Institute Summer School, 1996; UA086.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Institute [Correspondence], 1997; UA086.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Mailing List, 1997; UA086.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Final Papers, 1997; UA086.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Pamela A. Doorley, 1997; UA086.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Edwin Huh, 1997; UA086.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Alpana Kumar, 1997; UA086.001.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - Katherine D. O'Meara, 1997; UA086.001.004.00009 (Box 4)
  - Ami B. Parekh, 1997; UA086.001.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - Erin Schultz, 1997; UA086.001.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - Kira Sherwood, 1997; UA086.001.004.00012 (Box 4)
  - Hibret Tilahun, 1997; UA086.001.004.00013 (Box 4)
  - Kate Holbein, 1998; UA086.001.004.00014 (Box 4)
  - Lynsey Miller, 1998; UA086.001.004.00015 (Box 4)
  - Andrew Curran, 1998; UA086.001.004.00016 (Box 4)
  - Jen Gieseking, 1998; UA086.001.004.00017 (Box 4)
  - Rae Kozar, 1998; UA086.001.004.00018 (Box 4)
  - Faculty Response, 1998; UA086.001.004.00019 (Box 4)
  - [Financials and Correspondence], 1998; UA086.001.004.00020 (Box 4)
  - [Mailing Labels], 1998; UA086.001.004.00021 (Box 4)
  - [Course Books, Memos], 1998; UA086.001.004.00022 (Box 4)
  - 8th Inst.- May 20- Wed Orientation, 1998; UA086.001.004.00023 (Box 4)
  - 21 May- Thurs. [Course Readings], 1998; UA086.001.004.00024 (Box 4)
  - 26 May- Tuesday [Course Readings], 1998; UA086.001.004.00025 (Box 4)
  - 29 May- Friday [Course Readings], 1998; UA086.001.004.00026 (Box 4)
  - 2 June- Tuesday, 1998; UA086.001.004.00027 (Box 4)
  - 5 June- Friday, 1998; UA086.001.004.00028 (Box 4)
  - 9 June- Tuesday, 1998; UA086.001.004.00029 (Box 4)
  - 12 June- Friday, 1998; UA086.001.004.00030 (Box 4)
  - 16 June- Tues. [Course Readings], 1998; UA086.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - 19 June- Fri. [Course Readings], 1998; UA086.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - 23 June- Tues. [Course Readings], 1998; UA086.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - 26 June- Fri. [Course Readings], 1998; UA086.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - 30 June- Tues. [Course Readings], 1998; UA086.001.005.00005 (Box 5)
  - 7 July- Tues. [Course Readings], 1998; UA086.001.005.00006 (Box 5)
  - 10 July- Fri. [Course Readings], 1998; UA086.001.005.00007 (Box 5)
  - 14 July- Tues. [Course Notes], 1998; UA086.001.005.00008 (Box 5)
  - 17 July- Fri. [Course Notes], 1998; UA086.001.005.00009 (Box 5)
  - From Hiroshima to Abolition, 1999; UA086.001.005.00010 (Box 5)
  - AGAPE-NCPLP, 1999; UA086.001.005.00011 (Box 5)
  - [Alyssa Moore], 1999; UA086.001.005.00012 (Box 5)
  - Karim AbdulMatin- IDDS, 1999; UA086.001.005.00013 (Box 5)
  - Jon Crowe- WFANE, 1999; UA086.001.005.00014 (Box 5)
  - Elizabeth Goldman- WAND, 1999; UA086.001.005.00015 (Box 5)
  - Jen Groskin- CPC, 1999; UA086.001.005.00016 (Box 5)
  - Kevin Heffel- AFSC, 1999; UA086.001.005.00017 (Box 5)
  - Jason Horst- MPA, 1999; UA086.001.005.00018 (Box 5)
  - Stephanie Manson- WAND, 1999; UA086.001.005.00019 (Box 5)
  - Aisatou Ngong- UUSC, 1999; UA086.001.005.00020 (Box 5)
  - Annaken Toews- IPPNW, 1999; UA086.001.005.00021 (Box 5)
  - Adam Weiss- MOBE, 1999; UA086.001.005.00022 (Box 5)
  - Lee Safran- WFANE- MPA, 1999; UA086.001.005.00023 (Box 5)
  - Courtney DeGeorge- CPC- MPA, 1999; UA086.001.005.00024 (Box 5)
  - Satgin Seraj, 1999; UA086.001.005.00025 (Box 5)
  - Jennifer Fleming- CPC- MPA, 1999; UA086.001.005.00026 (Box 5)
  - Jennifer Messier- MPA- MOBE, 1999; UA086.001.005.00027 (Box 5)
  - Lauren Rodan- PUGWASH- CPC, 1999; UA086.001.005.00028 (Box 5)
  - Tammy Flores- PUGWASH- AAAS, 1999; UA086.001.005.00029 (Box 5)
  - Jonathan Kenny- Director, Folder 1 of 3, 1999; UA086.001.005.00030 (Box 5)
  - Jonathan Kenny- Director, Folder 2 of 3, 1999; UA086.001.005.00031 (Box 5)
  - Jonathan Kenny- Director, Folder 3 of 3, 1999; UA086.001.005.00032 (Box 5)
  - Peace Inst. Eval., 1999; UA086.001.005.00033 (Box 5)
  - Peace Inst. '00 Evaluations, 2000; UA086.001.005.00034 (Box 5)
  - Khady Ba, 2000; UA086.001.005.00035 (Box 5)
  - Kathleen Bell, 2000; UA086.001.005.00036 (Box 5)
  - Louis Esparza, 2000; UA086.001.005.00037 (Box 5)
  - Anne Grenchus, 2000; UA086.001.005.00038 (Box 5)
  - Women Take Action, 2000; UA086.001.005.00039 (Box 5)
  - Bill Hershey, 2000; UA086.001.005.00040 (Box 5)
  - Jennifer Hirano, 2000; UA086.001.005.00041 (Box 5)
  - Rania Jamal, 2000; UA086.001.005.00042 (Box 5)
  - Shilpa Patel, 2000; UA086.001.005.00043 (Box 5)
  - Jake Reid, 2000; UA086.001.005.00044 (Box 5)
  - The Tufts Daily, 2000; UA086.001.005.00045 (Box 5)
  - Organization Proposals, 2000; UA086.001.005.00046 (Box 5)
  - Project Abolition/ NCPLP, 2000; UA086.001.006.00001 (Box 6)
  - Peace Inst. Stipends, TA Paperwork, 2000; UA086.001.006.00002 (Box 6)
  - Stipend Paperwork, 2000; UA086.001.006.00003 (Box 6)
  - Ploughshares-Rubin, 2000; UA086.001.006.00004 (Box 6)
  - Molly Jackson-Watts, 2000; UA086.001.006.00005 (Box 6)
  - Lauren Rodan, 2000; UA086.001.006.00006 (Box 6)
  - Laura Subramanian, 2000; UA086.001.006.00007 (Box 6)
  - Ezra Golberstein, 2000; UA086.001.006.00008 (Box 6)
  - Ryan O'Sullivan, 2000; UA086.001.006.00009 (Box 6)
  - Brent Elrod, 2000; UA086.001.006.00010 (Box 6)
  - Jana Frey, 2000; UA086.001.006.00011 (Box 6)
  - Brande Flamez, 2000; UA086.001.006.00012 (Box 6)
  - Barbara Plank, 2000; UA086.001.006.00013 (Box 6)
  - Biljana Radonjic, 2000; UA086.001.006.00014 (Box 6)
  - Suman Shrestha, 2000; UA086.001.006.00015 (Box 6)
  - Arjun Ghataney, 2000; UA086.001.006.00016 (Box 6)
  - Om Nath Siwakoti, 2000; UA086.001.006.00017 (Box 6)
  - Chris Hamilton, 2000; UA086.001.006.00018 (Box 6)
  - Thomas Tchetmi, 2000; UA086.001.006.00019 (Box 6)
  - Katie Donahue, 2000; UA086.001.006.00020 (Box 6)
  - Sean Quinn, 2000; UA086.001.006.00021 (Box 6)
  - Final Papers, Summer Peace Institute, 2000; UA086.001.006.00022 (Box 6)
  - Julia Goodman, 2000; UA086.001.006.00023 (Box 6)
  - Nancy Harris, 2000; UA086.001.006.00024 (Box 6)
  - Ginette Chapman, 2000; UA086.001.006.00025 (Box 6)
  - Wesley Alexander, 2000; UA086.001.006.00026 (Box 6)
  - Casey Harris, 2000; UA086.001.006.00027 (Box 6)
  - Brian Ledyard, 2000; UA086.001.006.00028 (Box 6)
  - Cris Masters, 2000; UA086.001.006.00029 (Box 6)
  - Helen Rueda, 2000; UA086.001.006.00030 (Box 6)
  - Zack Blumberg, 2000; UA086.001.006.00031 (Box 6)
  - Chih-Kuo Chang, 2000; UA086.001.006.00032 (Box 6)
  - John D. Houghkirk Jr., York College of Pennsylvania, 2001; UA086.001.006.00033 (Box 6)
  - Luc Schuster, Pomona College, 2001; UA086.001.006.00034 (Box 6)
  - Brian Lobel, University of Michigan- Ann Arbor, 2001; UA086.001.006.00035 (Box 6)
  - Paul Isaac Ewenstein, Tufts University, 2001; UA086.001.006.00036 (Box 6)
  - Marcella Rae Fleming, University of Oklahoma, 2001; UA086.001.006.00037 (Box 6)
  - Jessie L. Hughes, Williamette University, 2001; UA086.001.006.00038 (Box 6)
  - Annie Welch, University of St. Thomas, 2001; UA086.001.006.00039 (Box 6)
  - Rana E. Abdul-Aziz, Tufts University, 2001; UA086.001.006.00040 (Box 6)
  - Jennika Arkell, Tufts University, 2001; UA086.001.006.00041 (Box 6)
  - Lena Graber, Wesleyan University, 2001; UA086.001.006.00042 (Box 6)
  - Elizabeth Fiedler, Bucknell University, 2001; UA086.001.006.00043 (Box 6)
  - Ming Hua Li, Tufts University, 2001; UA086.001.006.00044 (Box 6)
  - Rachel Jones, Tufts University, 2001; UA086.001.006.00045 (Box 6)
  - Rita Mercado, Tufts University, 2001; UA086.001.006.00046 (Box 6)
  - Vinay C. Reddy, Miami University, 2001; UA086.001.006.00047 (Box 6)
  - Peace Inst. '01 Evaluations, 2001; UA086.001.006.00048 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, Summer Planning, 2001; UA086.001.006.00049 (Box 6)
  - New Voices- AFSC, 2001; UA086.001.006.00050 (Box 6)
  - Course Notes, 2001; UA086.001.006.00051 (Box 6)
  - Course Notes, 2001; UA086.001.006.00052 (Box 6)
  - Course Notes, 2001; UA086.001.006.00053 (Box 6)
  - Course Notes, 2001; UA086.001.006.00054 (Box 6)
  - Course Notes, 2001; UA086.001.006.00055 (Box 6)
  - Course Notes, 2001; UA086.001.006.00056 (Box 6)
  - Course Notes, June, 2001; UA086.001.006.00057 (Box 6)
  - Course Notes, 2001; UA086.001.006.00058 (Box 6)
  - Course Notes, 2001; UA086.001.006.00059 (Box 6)
  - Course Notes, 2001; UA086.001.006.00060 (Box 6)
  - Course Notes, 2001; UA086.001.006.00061 (Box 6)
  - Course Notes, 2001; UA086.001.006.00062 (Box 6)
  - Course Notes, 2001; UA086.001.006.00063 (Box 6)
  - Course Notes, 2001; UA086.001.006.00064 (Box 6)
  - Stop the New Arms Race! Participant Kit, 2001; UA086.001.006.00065 (Box 6)
  - Stop the New Arms Race! Briefing Kit, 2001; UA086.001.006.00066 (Box 6)
  - Course Notes, 2001; UA086.001.006.00067 (Box 6)
  - Course Notes, 2001; UA086.001.006.00068 (Box 6)
  - Course Notes, 2001; UA086.001.006.00069 (Box 6)
  - Mystic Watershed Collaborative, 2001; UA086.001.007.00001 (Box 7)
  - Mystic Watershed Inst. Related, 2001; UA086.001.007.00002 (Box 7)
  - River Institute Planning, 2001; UA086.001.007.00003 (Box 7)
  - Kevin Welsh, Tufts University, 2001; UA086.001.007.00004 (Box 7)
  - Ryan Torres, 2001; UA086.001.007.00005 (Box 7)
  - Miriam Stein, Brandeis, 2001; UA086.001.007.00006 (Box 7)
  - Martha Podren, Antioch New England, 2001; UA086.001.007.00007 (Box 7)
  - Joanne Davidson, University of Notre Dame, 2001; UA086.001.007.00008 (Box 7)
  - Elizabeth Bloomer, Virginia Tech, 2001; UA086.001.007.00009 (Box 7)
  - Rachel Zegerius, Antioch NE, 2001; UA086.001.007.00010 (Box 7)
  - Nailya Aliyeva, Indiana University, 2001; UA086.001.007.00011 (Box 7)
  - Hind Merheb, Tufts, 2001; UA086.001.007.00012 (Box 7)
  - Claire Kfouri, Univ. of Guelph, 2001; UA086.001.007.00013 (Box 7)
  - Rebecca Ross, Tufts University, 2001; UA086.001.007.00014 (Box 7)
  - Summer Institute Course Syllabi, 2002; UA086.001.007.00015 (Box 7)
  - Course Notes, 2002; UA086.001.007.00016 (Box 7)
  - Ramona Boodosingh, Tufts, 2002; UA086.001.007.00017 (Box 7)
  - Morgan Jenkins, Colby-Sawyer, 2002; UA086.001.007.00018 (Box 7)
  - Ariella Summit, Tufts, 2002; UA086.001.007.00019 (Box 7)
  - Imogen Wirth-Granlund, Temple, 2002; UA086.001.007.00020 (Box 7)
  - Katherine Regan, Tufts, 2002; UA086.001.007.00021 (Box 7)
  - Haley Schoenfeld, Tufts, 2002; UA086.001.007.00022 (Box 7)
  - Lyndsay Hazen, UVM, 2002; UA086.001.007.00023 (Box 7)
  - Simon Goldberg, Tufts, 2002; UA086.001.007.00024 (Box 7)
  - Rosemary O'Day, St. Bonaventure, 2002; UA086.001.007.00025 (Box 7)
  - Hollis Lauren Luzecky, Drake U. Law School, 2002; UA086.001.007.00026 (Box 7)
  - Eric Pescatore, Clark, 2002; UA086.001.007.00027 (Box 7)
  - Breck Baird, Tulane, 2002; UA086.001.007.00028 (Box 7)
  - Mystic Watershed Collaborative Steering Committee, 2002; UA086.001.007.00029 (Box 7)
  - NAAEE Proposal/ Conf., 2002; UA086.001.007.00030 (Box 7)
  - River Institute Planning, 2002; UA086.001.007.00031 (Box 7)
  - River Institute Journals, 2002; UA086.001.007.00032 (Box 7)
  - Course Notes, 2003; UA086.001.007.00033 (Box 7)
  - Course Notes, 2003; UA086.001.007.00034 (Box 7)
  - Course Notes, 2003; UA086.001.007.00035 (Box 7)
  - Course Notes, 2003; UA086.001.008.00001 (Box 8)
  - Course Notes, 2003; UA086.001.008.00002 (Box 8)
  - Course Notes, 2003; UA086.001.008.00003 (Box 8)
  - Course Notes, 2003; UA086.001.008.00004 (Box 8)
  - Course Notes, 2003; UA086.001.008.00005 (Box 8)
  - Course Notes, 2003; UA086.001.008.00006 (Box 8)
  - Course Notes, 2003; UA086.001.008.00007 (Box 8)
  - Course Notes, 2003; UA086.001.008.00008 (Box 8)
  - Course Notes, 2003; UA086.001.008.00009 (Box 8)
  - Course Notes, 2003; UA086.001.008.00010 (Box 8)
  - Mystic Herring Run Festival, 2003; UA086.001.008.00011 (Box 8)
  - River Institute Planning, 2003; UA086.001.008.00012 (Box 8)
  - Annie Scola, Maxwell/Syracuse, 2003; UA086.001.008.00013 (Box 8)
  - Juliette Lizeray, Tufts, 2003; UA086.001.008.00014 (Box 8)
  - Matt Cunningham, UIS, 2003; UA086.001.008.00015 (Box 8)
  - Rachael Edinger, Tufts UEP, 2003; UA086.001.008.00016 (Box 8)
  - Ata Suanda, Wesleyan Univ., 2003; UA086.001.008.00017 (Box 8)
  - Guillaume Turcotte, Temple Univ., 2003; UA086.001.008.00018 (Box 8)
  - John Healy, Indiana Univ., 2003; UA086.001.008.00019 (Box 8)
  - Kate Morkeski, UMASS Amherst, 2003; UA086.001.008.00020 (Box 8)
  - Lisa Fishlin, Tufts, 2003; UA086.001.008.00021 (Box 8)
  - Sarah Rosenberg, Clark Univ., 2003; UA086.001.008.00022 (Box 8)
  - Melissa Henry, Penn State, 2003; UA086.001.008.00023 (Box 8)
  - Beatrice Huang, Yale School, 2003; UA086.001.008.00024 (Box 8)
  - Tax Exemption Forms, 2003; UA086.001.008.00025 (Box 8)
  - Inst. Research, 2003; UA086.001.008.00026 (Box 8)
  - Student Papers, 2001; UA086.001.008.00027 (Box 8)
  - Course Syllabi, Brochures, 1998 -- 2001; UA086.001.008.00028 (Box 8)
  - Inst. Syllabus/ WRR Info, 1998 -- 2001; UA086.001.008.00029 (Box 8)
  - Funders Info, 1990 -- 1995; UA086.001.008.00030 (Box 8)
  - Inst. Research/ Data/ Etc., 1990 -- 1995; UA086.001.008.00031 (Box 8)
  - EDF/ Inst. Misc., 1990 -- 1995; UA086.001.008.00032 (Box 8)
  - Trust for Public Land Case Studies, 1996; UA086.001.008.00033 (Box 8)
  - Internship Agreements, 1991 -- 2003; UA086.001.008.00034 (Box 8)
  - Environmental Diversity Forum, 1996; UA086.001.008.00035 (Box 8)
  - Michelle Markestyn, 2002; UA086.001.009.00001 (Box UA086 Shared 1)
  - MWC Steering Committee, 2000 -- 2001; UA086.001.009.00002 (Box UA086 Shared 1)
  - Mystic River Watershed Association, 1999 -- 2002; UA086.001.009.00003 (Box UA086 Shared 1)
  - Paul Robbins- LAWNS, 2001 -- 2005; UA086.001.009.00004 (Box UA086 Shared 1)
  - Newsletters, 2002 -- 2005; UA086.001.009.00005 (Box UA086 Shared 1)
  - River Inst., 2002 -- 2005; UA086.001.009.00006 (Box UA086 Shared 1)
- Curricula, 1980 -- 2010; UA086.002; 3.6 Linear Feet
  This series contains files related to curricula development for Peace and Justice Studies courses and other affiliated classes and internships from 1980 to 2006. The series includes files related to internship revision, professional development and experiential education literature, service learning, and project proposals.
  This series is arranged by date and course number.
  Open for research.
  - Curriculum Development, 1980; UA086.002.009.00007 (Box UA086 Shared 1)
  - INTRO Course Proposal, 1986 -- 1987; UA086.002.009.00008 (Box UA086 Shared 1)
  - Community Leadership Practicum, 1990; UA086.002.009.00009 (Box UA086 Shared 1)
  - Title VI Grant, 1995; UA086.002.009.00010 (Box UA086 Shared 1)
  - CSL Project, 1997; UA086.002.009.00011 (Box UA086 Shared 1)
  - Cross-Class Coalition/ Multicultural Community, 2005; UA086.002.009.00012 (Box UA086 Shared 1)